blumentals.net 2017-06-21

# Blumentals Software - Privacy Policy

This privacy policy discloses the privacy practices for Blumentals Software websites and online services operated by Blumentals Solutions SIA. This privacy policy applies solely to information collected by the following websites 

  * www.blumentals.net
  * www.blumentals.de
  * www.rapidseotool.com
  * www.easymenumaker.com
  * www.easycssmenu.com
  * www.easygifanimator.net
  * www.magicbuttonmaker.com
  * www.webuilderapp.com
  * www.rapidphpeditor.com
  * www.htmlpad.net
  * www.rapidcsseditor.com
  * www.surfblocker.com

## Information Gathering and Usage

We are the sole owners of the information collected on this site. We only collect personal information that you voluntarily give us via email, web-based fill-in forms and other direct contact from you.

When you use Blumentals Software web site or services, our servers automatically record information that your browser sends to every website you visit, such as time of day, browser type, referring Web site address and your IP address.

When you register for Blumentals Software services, we may ask for information such as your name, company name, email address, billing address.

When you subscribe to our e-mail newsletter, you will be required to provide your e-mail address and to confirm your subscription by clicking a web link in your subscription confirmation e-mail.

When you place an order online with us, you will be redirected to an SSL-secured website operated by our trusted billing merchant and there you will be required to provide personal information (including your credit card details) to our billing merchant. Information you provide to our billing merchant will be processed in accordance with its privacy policy (available at the bottom of billing pages) and you are therefore advised to review such policy prior to purchase. Blumentals Software will have access to your full name, company name, address and contact info, but not to your credit card or any other payment account data.

We may use collected information for the following general purposes: products and services provision, billing, identification and authentication, services improvement, contact, and research.

**Unless you ask us not to, we may contact you via email in the future to tell you about specials, new products or services, or changes to this privacy policy.** If you do not want to receive such information, **you can easily opt-out from future communication at anytime** by [removing your email address](https://www.blumentals.net/newsletter.php) from our mailing lists.

Except as described in this statement, **we will never willfully disclose your personal information outside of Blumentals Software** without your consent.

We may share your personal information with third parties only if we believe such action is necessary to: (a) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request; (b) investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities or suspected fraud; (c) protect and defend the rights or property of Blumentals Software; or (d) act in situations involving potential threats to the personal safety of any person.

We do not collect or store any credit or debit card numbers, financial account numbers, national identity, pension, social security, tax ID, health care, or driver's license numbers.

## Cookies

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. None of the cookies used by this website contain any personal information. Below is a detailed list of cookies that this website may set:

  * **Session cookies.** These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the website and use its features. Without these cookies, services you have asked for, like logging into your account, cannot be provided.
  * **Cookies that remember your choice.** Some cookies used on this website allow the website to remember choices you make (such as your preferred language).
  * **Google Analytics cookies.** These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use this information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form.
  * **Third party service provider cookies.** Cookies can be set by the following third party services used on this website: Google Analytics, Facebook Like Button, Twitter Follow button, Google +1 button, YouTube videos. Some of these cookies may be used to track your behaviour on other websites and we have no control over this as these cookies are not set by our own website.

You can usually modify your browser settings to disable cookies. However, by disabling cookies, or certain types of cookie, you may hinder your user experience on this and other websites, or prevent them from working entirely.

**By continuing to use this website without adjusting your browser's cookie settings, you agree that we can place the cookies mentioned above on your device.**

## Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics to understand how the site is being used in order to improve the user experience. User data is all anonymous. You can find out more about Google's position on privacy as regards its analytics service at [www.google.com](https://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html)

## Software License Validation

Our software may attempt to contact remote servers over the Internet in order to complete the license activation process and validate the right to use the software on your computer. No personally identifiable information will be transmitted during this process, except to the extent that IP address may be considered personally identifiable in some jurisdictions.

## Data Storage

Blumentals Software uses reputable third party vendors and hosting partners to provide the necessary hardware, software, networking, storage, and related technology required to run Blumentals Software website and services.

## Changes

Blumentals Software may periodically update this policy. When we do, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of the information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.

## Questions

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please contact us.
